we are the Democrats since 1828 our
great party has played a major role in
participating in the political process
that has produced what is arguably the
greatest Republic the world has ever
seen we've produced generation after
generation of leaders whom despite their
faults have helped established and
maintained a country that has served in
the main as a beacon of light and hope
to the desperate masses of the world
yearning in those immemorial words to
breathe free over those nearly 200 years
we have all worked together despite our
differences to produce a society we're
desperate want is a rarity where
hard-working men and women can produce a
better future for themselves and their
children and where the arbitrary
disadvantages that have in the past held
so many of us back and deprived others
of our genuine talents having good faith
being continually reduced and minimized
nothing is perfect and neither is our
country but we have built together a
stable secure exciting dynamic community
and can all in consequence look forward
to an even better tomorrow but we as
Democrats have faltered in our duty in
recent years we have allowed the
discourse within our ranks to become
increasingly dominated by a tiny well
organized and disruptive minority who
have insisted evermore stridently that
our culture is a tyrannical destructive
patriarchy and that we are not sovereign
responsible individual citizens capable
of negotiating a shared and prosperous
peace but oppressive or oppressed
minority group members defined above all
by our sex race ethnicity and sexual
preference we have failed as well to
oppose the profoundly anti-american
claim that free speech is merely the
means by which the powerful protect
their interests and we have abandoned
our invaluable commitment to and
contract with the American working class
who toiled might
and often under conditions of extreme
deprivation to perform the back-breaking
labor so necessary to the creation of
our stellar country in doing so we
betrayed and insulted our primary
constituency and we squandered the
opportunity to elect the first woman to
the position of the presidency of the
United States then instead of taking
responsibility for our well deserved
failure and loss we insisted upon
vilifying those who defeated us
appropriately and honestly in the
honorable democratic process were sorry
we promised to return to the priorities
that made our party great we promised to
build and revitalize the vital
infrastructure whose construction
employs our trades people and whose use
is available to all we promise to insist
that our schools and those who conduct
the research upon which their methods
are founded abandon their divisive
ideology and teach our children the
knowledge and skills necessary to make
them respectable mature productive
reliable citizens we promise and have
already taken productive steps to reduce
the inevitable corruption that tends to
take hold of even the greatest and most
alert of states were the Democrats we
did not uphold our responsibility to the
American people and were justly and
properly sorry for that we promise to
clean our house we promise to draw
divisions between the key and
time-honored principles that unite us
all and the divisive identity politics
that is threatening to reduce us to an
ignoble squabbling and dangerously
polarized tribalism we're the Democrats
we hope you'll forgive us and we promise
by the sacred social compact defined by
our unalienable individual rights to act
responsibly and carefully and do better
together long may our great country
prosper